Finding Aid for M-Pathways Project (University of Michigan) publications, 1994-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
M-Pathways Project (University of Michigan) publications 1994-2001, 1998-2001
University of Michigan. M-Pathways Project.
3 linear feet
0111; Bimu; 2
Formed in 1996, the M-Pathways Project was charged with the design and implementation of new administrative information systems for the University of Michigan. Until this point, administrative business transactions were performed using the Michigan Terminal System (MTS).Includes a prospectus describing the M-Pathways Project and its goals entitled M-Pathways Connecting People and Information: Project Description and Request for Comments. Also contains end user training manuals and printouts of email announcements and the electronic newsletter "SA Update" published by the Student Administration System.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications were received in November 2000 from the M-Pathways Project (Donor No. 8995 ).
No further regular accessions are expected.
M-Pathways Publications are open for research without restriction.
For historical note, please consult the M-Pathways Project (University of Michigan Records finding aid immediately finding aid.
The M-Pathways Project Publications are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications. The bulk of the publications document the training offered to prepare instructors to teach and university staff to learn the new data system.
Subjects:
M Pathways Project (University of Michigan); Information technology--Michigan.; PeopleSoft Software.
Genre Terms:
Manuals.; Newsletters.; Prospectuses.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the M-Pathways Project. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
  The Unit Publications series includes announcements, brochures, invitations, newsletters, and prospectuses. The e-mail printout announcements dating from 2001 to the present report changes in the system, shut-downs for maintenance, and upgrades to the system. The newsletter Trans-Express was written to communicated the changes taking place in the new stream-lined record-keeping system An undated prospectus describes the M-Pathways Project and its goals. There is also a 1997 prospectus detailing the M-Pathways Project and requesting comments on the system.
  - Announcements (e-mail printouts)
    - 2001-2003 (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - 1998 undated (Box 1)
  - Invitations
    - PeopleSoft Beta Partners at the University of Michigan, April 1996 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Trans-Express, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Prospectuses
    - M-Pathways Connecting People and Information: Project Description and Request for Comments undated (Box 1)
    - Project Description and Request for Comments, revised 1997 (Box 1)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from subordinate offices, departments, programs and organizations within the M-Pathways Project. These publications are arranged alphabetically by the creating sub-unit.
  The bulk of the publications are in the Sub-Unit Publications series. The training manuals are divided into seven subseries, arranged alphabetically, including the Financial Administrations System, Human Resources, the M-Pathways Information System, the Space Management System, the Student Administration System, and early training offered to those who would teach the record creators and users. Six of these subseries contain end user manuals dating from 1998 to 2001. In addition the Student Administration System subseries contains printed e-mail announcements regarding curriculum and student administration dating from 2000 to the present. This subseries also includes the e-mail newsletter (print-outs) SA Update dating from 2000 to the present. The seventh subseries contains manuals dating from 1994 to 1997 documenting the recruiting, admissions, and financial aid functions of the PeopleSoft Student
  - Data Delivery
    - Manuals
      - Data Warehouse--Using BusinessObjects: Training Guide, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Data Warehouse
    - Dictionaries
      - Payroll: Data Dictionary, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Financial Administration System
    - Course Descriptions
      - End User Training Curriculum undated (Box 1)
    - Manuals, End User Training
      - Advanced Budgeting, August 1998 (Box 1)
      - Advanced Purchase Orders Lab Exercises, undated (Box 1)
      - Budgeting II, January 1999 (Box 1)
      - Fundamentals of Budgeting, May 1998 (Box 1)
      - General Ledger I, April 1998 (Box 1)
      - General Ledger II, April 1998 (Box 1)
      - General Ledger III: Advanced ChartFields Lab, April 1998 (Box 1)
      - General Ledger III: Advanced General Ledger, June, 1998 (Box 1)
      - General Ledger/Procurement Data Warehouse Reporting, August, 1998 (Box 1)
      - General Ledger Reporting, October 1998 (Box 1)
      - Payables PO Voucher Procedures, June 1998 (Box 1)
      - PO Auditing Training Manual, June 1999 (Box 1)
      - Procurement I and II, October, 1998 (Box 1)
      - Purchasing Procedures, May 1998 (Box 1)
      - Reconciling P-Cards Using M-Pathways, August, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Financial Information Systems Procurement Team
    - Flowcharts and Narratives (Box 1)
    - Current Procurement Processes, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Financials Training
    - Manuals
      - General Ledger Reporting I: Training Guide, 2001 (Box 1)
      - General Ledger 7.5 Upgrade: Change Guide, 2001 (Box 1)
      - Introduction to M-Pathways and ChartFields: Training Guide, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Financials Training (cont.)
    - Manuals (cont.)
      - Procurement I: The Purchase Order: Training Guide includes The PO "Dance", 2001 (Box 1)
      - Procurement II: The Requisition: Training Manual, 2001 (Box 1)
      - Procurement III: The Non-PO Voucher: Training Guide, 2001 (Box 1)
      - Reconciling P-Cards Using M-Pathways: Training Guide, 2001 (Box 1)
  - HRMS Training (Box 2)
    - Manuals
      - Data Warehouse--Understanding Human Resource Data: Training Guide, 2001 (Box 2)
      - Data Warehouse: Understanding Payroll Data: Training Guide, 2001 (Box 2)
      - HRMS Overview: Training Manual, 2001 (Box 2)
  - PeopleSoft Student Administration, Release 6
    - Manuals
      - The Art of Implementation, February 1995 (Box 2)
      - Exploring Admissions, March 1997 (Box 2)
      - Exploring Financial Aid, March 1997 (Box 2)
      - Exploring Student Financials, March 1997 (Box 2)
      - PeopleSoft Hardware and Software Requirements: Technical Guidelines for Success with PeopleSoft Products, PeopleTools 3.2, December 1994 (Box 2)
      - Setting Up Admissions, April 1997 (Box 2)
      - Viewing Summary Recruiting and Admissions Information, April 1997 (Box 2)
  - Procurement and General Ledger Training
    - Introduction to M-Pathways and ChartFields for Organization Managers, September 1998 (Box 2)
  - Space Management
    - Manuals
      - Space Survey Course: Training Guide
        - 1998 (Box 2)
        - 2000 (Box 2)
  - Student Administration
    - Announcements
      - E-Mail Announcements Printouts
        - Curriculum 2000-2001 (Box 2)
        - Student Administration 2000-2001 (Box 2)
    - Manuals, End User Training
      - Admissions I, November, 1998 (Box 2)
      - Advanced Admissions II, September, 1998 (Box 2)
      - Advanced Admissions III, April, 1998 (Box 2)
      - Admissions Communications Update, Self-Study Guide, September 1998 (Box 2)
      - Admissions for Student Financial and Cashier's Office Staff Members, October 1998 (Box 2)
      - Admissions Reporting Update, September, 1998 (Box 2)
      - Admissions, Roster Data Dictionary, December, 1998 (Box 2)
      - Comments Self-Study, April 28, 2000 (Box 2)
      - Data Warehouse-Admissions Roster Tables Code Reference, October 1998 (Box 2)
      - Data Warehouse-Recruiting and Admissions Data, January 1999 (Box 2)
      - Data Warehouse-Understanding SA01 Admissions Roster Data, January, 1999 (Box 3)
      - Data Warehouse-Using Business Objects, October, 1998 (Box 3)
      - Degree Progress Overview, September 2000 (Box 3)
      - Fundamentals of Recruiting, March, 1998 (Box 3)
      - Fundamentals of Recruiting and Admissions, November, 1998 (Box 3)
      - Introduction to M-Pathways, November 1998 (Box 3)
      - Introduction to Recruiting/Admissions Checklists, September 1998 (Box 3)
      - Introduction to Recruiting/Admissions Communications, September 1998 (Box 3)
      - Introduction to Recruiting and Admissions Reporting, September 1998 (Box 3)
      - Introduction to Student Financials, Self-Study Guide, June 2000 (Box 3)
      - Mass Change for Recruiting/Admissions, October 1998 (Box 3)
      - Overview of Financial Aid, Self-Study Guide, June 2000 (Box 3)
      - Recruiting and Admissions Basics, October 1998 (Box 3)
      - Student Administration Overview, October, 1999 (Box 3)
      - Student Financials Service Indicators, Self-Study Guide, June 2000 (Box 3)
      - Student Group Tracking, Self Study Guide, June 2000 (Box 3)
      - Student Records Academic Advising Office Procedures, Self Study Guide, June, 2000 (Box 3)
      - Student Records Basics, Self Study Guide, June 2000 (Box 3)
      - Understanding Student Program/Plan Panels, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Newsletters, (e-mail printouts)
      - SA Update, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Training
    - Manuals, End User Training
      - Coaching Program--Procurement: Training Guide, 1998 (Box 3)
      - Introduction to ChartFields, undated (Box 3)
      - Organization Manager, June 1998 (Box 3)
      - Organization Manager (With Prerequisites), June 1998 (Box 3)
      - Training Job Aids (various dates) (Box 3)
      - Train the Trainer, January, 1998 (Box 3)